(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T13:40:04.602887",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
風邪引くの
Catching a cold,
catching a cold.
お布団なくて寒い
It's cold without a futon.
お布団剥がされて寒い
It's cold with the futon pulled away.
夜明けにあなたが来る
You come at dawn,
あなたが笑っている
and you are smiling.
きっと私には見えないと思っている
You must think I can't see you.
そっと手を伸ばして
Gently reaching out your hand,
一体何をするつもり？
what on earth do you intend to do?
寝たふりをして過ごす
Spending time pretending to sleep,
少しだけ温かくなる
getting just a little warmer.
隣であなたが眠る
You sleep right beside me,
うるさい寝言は無視して
ignoring your noisy sleeptalking.
ああ昨日の夜ご飯何食べたか思い出せない
Ah, I can't remember what I ate for dinner yesterday.
ああいつもの朝 どうか世界がほろぶように
Ah, an ordinary morning, please let the world crumble.
風邪引いてて知らないの
You don't know I caught a cold.
お布団ないと寒い
It's cold without a futon,
お布団隠されて寒い
it's cold with the futon hidden.
震える指先タッチ
Shivering fingertips touching,
吐息はストーブみたい
my breath is like a stove.
きっとすぐには起かないと思っている
You must think I won't wake up anytime soon.
側で見てる
Watching right by your side,
一体何をするつもり？ フッカフカ
what on earth do you intend to do? So fluffy...
手袋でも僕はタヌキ
Even with gloves, I'm a tanuki.
伝わる温もりはコゲツ
The warmth conveyed is burnt.
丸まる体ふたつ この際悪夢は無視して
Two curled-up bodies, ignore the nightmare this once.
寝たふりをして過ごす
Spending time pretending to sleep,
少しだけ温かくなる
getting just a little warmer.
隣であなたが眠る
You sleep right beside me,
うるさい寝言は無視して
ignoring your noisy sleeptalking.
重なるおでこにキスをして
Kissing our overlapping foreheads.
はーいということで月の上のからロボ子の4周年記念ライブにみんな来てくれてありがとう！
So, thank you everyone for coming to Roboco-san's 4th anniversary live stream from on the moon!
あ、やばい近づくと星空が壁紙みたいになってるのがばれてしまう！まずいまずいまずい
Ah, oh no, if I get too close, it'll give away that the starry sky is just like wallpaper! Oh no, oh no, oh no!
え、でも見てこのロボ子の乗ってる次...
Um, but look at the next thing Roboco is riding...
おはよう！
Good morning!
あ、すごい
Ah, amazing.
一番星、輝く一番星にロボ子なってしまった気分だよ、えへへ！
I feel like I've become the brightest star, ehehe!
はい、というわけで、みんな今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Yes, so everyone, thank you for coming today!
盛り上がって、行くぞ！どうだ！
Get hyped, let's go! How's this?
ロボ子は座って、盛り上がっていまーす。
Roboco is sitting here getting hyped.
本日はですね、ロボ子4周年記念ライブのハッシュタグを使っていっぱいツイートしてほしいんだよ。
Today, I want you to tweet a lot using the hashtag for Roboco's 4th anniversary live.
可愛いロボ子をいっぱい、いっぱい撮ってほしいな。
I want you to take lots and lots of cute pictures of Roboco.
本日のライブはですね、なんとゲストもサムネで公開していっぱいいるんだけれども歌もいっぱいうたうんですが
Today's live has guests revealed in the thumbnails, and there are lots of them, and I'll be singing lots of songs too, but...
なんとアップデートがチラチラチラチラとあるらしいということでね
Apparently, there are updates coming here and there, so...
何が一一体アップデートされたのか、楽しみに見ててくだサーイ！
please look forward to seeing what exactly has been updated!
え、みんな何がアップデートされると思う？
Eh, what do you guys think will be updated?
新衣装？新衣装？
New outfit? New outfit?
ねえ、そう、みんなちょっと考えといて。
Hey, yeah, everyone think about it.
それをこのね、絶対なんとかだと思うとか、これなんとかじゃないの？
Like, "It's definitely this!" or "Isn't it this?"
っていうのもぜひこちらのタグでロボ子トレンドを目指したいのでみんなツイートしてトレンドに乗せてくれたまえ頼むぞ！
I want to aim for #RobocoTrend with this tag, so please tweet it and get it on the trending list, I'm counting on you!
え、かわいすぎ？え、この女、かわいすぎ？え、なんと今日で4周年記念ライブ？
Eh, too cute? Eh, this girl, too cute? Eh, today is the 4th anniversary live?
かわいいでしょ？
Isn't it cute?
ねぇ、初見の方も常連のロボさんも、ロボ子のことをいっぱい好きになってもらえるようにロボ子もダンスも歌もいっぱい練習したので、楽しみに楽しみに最後まで1時間たっぷり楽しみにしていってください！
Hey, newcomers and regular Robosa alike, I practiced dancing and singing a lot so that you'll all grow to love Roboco even more, so please enjoy yourself to the fullest for the whole hour!
噛むのはご愛嬌ということで、
Tripping over my words is just part of my charm,
ロボ子、ロボ子だから許してほしいんだよ。はーい！
so please forgive me since I'm Roboco. Yay!
というわけでね、さっそくなんかちょっと今ロボ子は地上にいないんだけど、
So, right now, Roboco isn't actually on the ground...
あれ？なんかちょっと下のほうから匂いがするからちょっと降りてみようかなって思ったけど、あれ？意外と月が、よいしょっ！
Huh? I smell something from down below, so I thought I'd try climbing down, but wait, surprisingly the moon is—whoops!
あれ？なんか月ってこんなに身近な存在だったんだね。あれ？結構近い存在だったのかもしれない。
Huh? I guess the moon has always been such a familiar presence. Huh? Maybe it was quite close after all.
降りちゃったじゃあ月バイバイしよう。お月さま戻れ！バイバラーイ！
I got down, so let's say bye to the moon. Moon, go back! Bye-bye!
帰れない。帰れなかった。
I can't go back. I couldn't go back.
ちょっと後で魔法の呪文をかけるわ。
I'll cast a magic spell later.
というわけでですね、ちょっといい匂いがするから、あんまりちょっと、ん？なんか？ふんふんふん。
So, um, it smells really nice, so a bit... hmm? What is it? Hmm hmm hmm.
あ、ちょっとロボ子向こうに何かいい香りがするそうなのでちょっとみんな走ってくれよ！ちょっと待ってて！行くぞー！
Ah, Roboco smells something nice over there, so everyone run! Wait for me! Here we go!
とりゃあー！
Hyah!
なんとこの音、おー！
What is this sound? Oh!
今日はなんか、ここのカフェでイベントやってるらしいよ。え？
Today, apparently there's an event happening at this cafe. Eh?
カフェ？どう見てもステージ味なのだだけれど、これ。
A cafe? It totally looks like a stage though, this.
いらっしゃいませー！おや？
Welcome! Oh?
え、何？もしかして、アンポンタンの方ですかね？
Eh, what? Could you by any chance be a bunch of idiots?
あ、ほんと？ポタンストーズの、え、ぽぽ、あん、あんたんと、えー、ハラペロボ子です。
Ah, really? We're the Pontan Stoz—uh, Popo, Antan, and, um, hungry Roboco.
違うでしょ！あんたんと、アキ・ローゼンタール、そして
That's not it! Antan, Aki Rosenthal, and...
ポンタントンのロボ子です。
Pontanton's Roboco.
なんかポンしてんだよ、こいつ。
She keeps messing up, this one.
そして、そして、坦々麺の姫森ルーナなのだなのだ！
And, and, Himemori Luna of Tantanmen!
クソ、噛み続けなかった！
Damn, I couldn't stop messing up!
噛み続けんだよ、もう。いや、普段からね高精度なポンをありがとうございます。
You keep messing up! Well, thank you as always for your high-precision blunders.
なのだなのだよ。え、でも2人とも何しにここに来たの？
That's right, nano. Eh, but why did you two come here?
いやいやいや、どころ、今日もなんかイベントが開催されてるらしいんだけど、知ってる？
No no no, wait, apparently an event is being held today, did you know?
そうそうそう。確かここ、実はアイドルステージ風のカフェなんだよね。
That's right, that's right. Actually, this is an idol-stage-style cafe.
え、もしかして、うわさの4周年イベントってやつ？そういうこと？
Eh, could this be that rumored 4th-anniversary event? Is that it?
そうそう、なのだなのだ、ふう。あ、ルーナついてきてるか？
That's right, nano nano, phew. Ah, is Luna keeping up?
なんだろ、ロボ子、なんだろ？
What is Roboco-san...
なんだろ？
What could it be?
おいしいもの期待してたんだよ
We've been expecting something good.
こちらのルナは。
Here in Luna's case...
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
姫様ようにパンケーキもね、
For Princess, we also have pancakes,
こちら、え、透明なパンケーキと
uh, here... transparent pancakes...
なっております。
We have those prepared!
おーい！
Oh!
心が綺麗な人にしか見えませんと。
They're only visible to pure-hearted people!
おいしそう。
Sounds delicious.
見えねえわ！
It's invisible!
おい！舐めてんのか！
Oi! Don't look down on it!
あれ、心がまだまだのご様子ですね。
Well, it seems your heart still needs work.
まったく。
My goodness.
で、どうなの、注文はここできんの？
So, can we place orders here?
できるに決まってるじゃないですの！
You can if you want!
おやあ。
Alright!
じゃあ、ちょっと同じメニューさ、頼みたいなって思うんだけど、
Then how about we order the usual menu?
一緒にいいですか、行ってもらっても。
Is it okay if we all go together?
しょうがないね！
No way!
ありありありだなの！
It's alright, isn't it?
じゃあ、行きますよ。
Then let's go!
ご注文は？
Our order is...
せーの、ぼなぺてぃーと♡S
Bon Appétit! ♡ S
ふたり合わせるぞー！いくぞー！
Let's go to sleep together!
Smile・Sweet・Sister・Sadistic
Smile, Sweet, Sister, Sadistic,
Surprise・Service・We are スティーレ！！
Surprise, Service, We are Sti-re-!!
ぼなぺてぃーと♡S
Bon Appétit! ♡ S
さあ 扉を開けて 未知なるパラダイス
Open the door to an unknown paradise,
体感しよう おいいで おいいでYOU
Let's experience it, eat up, eat up, YOU!
そう キミを待つのは 不思議なオアシス
Awaiting you is a mysterious oasis.
ほっこり日常に ちょっとだけSpice
Just a little spice for the peaceful everyday life.
ぐーるんぐーるん 当店自慢のフレーバー
Round and round, our shop's proud flavor,
サービスサービス ご褒美タイム
Service, service, compliment time!
おもてなし ココロ こめて
Hospitality, pouring our hearts into it.
Welcome to...
わーい！ 私達と一緒にめくるめくワンダーデイリードリーム
Yay! Wandering through wonderland together with us,
愛情マシマシ 煩悩ナデナデ 誠心誠意つとめます
Affection to the max, worries nade nade, we put our hearts into it.
いぇーす！ キミの元気チャージにひと役かえるかな
Yay! Helping out a bit with your energy charge,
こーいう感じも あーいう感じも
This kind of feeling, or that kind of feeling,
意外と悪くないでしょ？
Might not be so bad after all, right?
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい
Buono Buono, we want to blend,
キミにきゅんきゅんきゅん ハートにぱんちぱんちぱんちっ
Giving you kyuun kyuun kyuun, and heart panchi panchi panchi!
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい
Buono Buono, we want to blend,
お口にあいますか？ お口にあうといいな♪
Does it suit your taste? I hope it suits you♪
ぼなぺてぃーと♡
Bon Appétit! ♡
千客万来ー！！
Customers, thank you very much!!
ちょっと、なんか、不本意ながらも
Wait, somehow, even though it's reluctant,
いつだって需要は斜め上
Demand is always leaning diagonally upwards.
そんじゃ、いっか、本当の私は
So, actually, the real me is...
シークレットモードで営業スイッチオン
Operating in secret mode, switch on!
ぐーるんぐーるん キミ仕様のフレーバー
Round and round, a flavor tailored just for you,
サービスサービス 極上タイム
Service, service, supreme time!
癒やしとは かくあるべき
Healing is how it should be.
Welcome to...
わーい！ 私達のお店に本日はようこそ
Yay! A warm welcome to our shop today,
おかえり待ってた リピートうれしいな
Welcome back, I was waiting, repeat makes me so happy.
店員一同歓迎
All staff welcome you.
いぇーす！ キミのお疲れ様にピッタリのレシピで
Yay! A recipe perfect for when you're tired,
こーゆーどーかな あーゆーありかな
How about this, or how about that,
よろこんできて貰えてるかな
I hope you are enjoying it.
Smile・Sweet・Sister・Sadistic
Smile, Sweet, Sister, Sadistic,
Small・Strange・Serious・Secret・Super Girl
Small, Strange, Serious, Secret, Super Girl,
We are スティーレ！！
We are Sti-re-!!
さあ 扉を開けて ゆかいなパラダイス
Now then, open the door to a joyful paradise,
こわがらずに おいいで、おいいで
Without breaking, eat up, eat up,
そう いつもの通りの毎日に いろどりとなそびごころ
Yes, every day just like always, colorful and playful,
めしませあえ ブレンド・S
A treat to make you smile, Blend S.
Welcome to...
わーい！ 私達と一緒にめくるめくワンダーデイリードリーム
Yay! Wandering through wonderland together with us,
愛情マシマシ 煩悩ナデナデ 誠心誠意つとめます
Affection to the max, worries nade nade, we put our hearts into it.
いぇーす！ キミの元気チャージにひと役かえるかな
Yay! Helping out a bit with your energy charge,
こーいう感じも あーいう感じも
This kind of feeling, or that kind of feeling,
意外と悪くないでしょ？
Might not be so bad after all, right?
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい
Buono Buono, we want to blend,
キミにきゅんきゅんきゅん ハートにぱんちぱんちぱんちっ
Giving you kyuun kyuun kyuun, and heart panchi panchi panchi!
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい
Buono Buono, we want to blend,
お口にあいますか？ お好みかせてね
Does it suit your taste? I hope you like it♪
さあ 扉を開けて 未知なるパラダイス
Open the door, to an unknown paradise,
ことなく置いて おいいで、おいいで
Without fail, leave it to us, come on, come on.
そう いつも通りの毎日に たどり着いた
Always the same everyday, reaching a new milestone.
あぁ 高鳴るココロ メリィゴラウンド
Ah, overflowing heart!
Welcome to...
わーい！ 私達と一緒にめくるめくワンダーデイリードリーム
Yay! Wandering through wonderland together with us,
愛情マシマシ 煩悩ナデナデ 誠心誠意つとめます
Affection to the max, worries nade nade, we put our hearts into it.
いぇーす！ キミの元気チャージにひと役かえるかな
Yay! Helping out a bit with your energy charge,
こーいう感じも あーいう感じも
This kind of feeling, or that kind of feeling,
意外と悪くないでしょ？
Might not be so bad after all, right?
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい
Buono Buono, we want to blend,
キミにきゅんきゅんきゅん ハートにぱんちぱんちぱんちっ
Giving you kyuun kyuun kyuun, and heart panchi panchi panchi!
Buono Buono ブレンドしたい
Buono Buono, we want to blend,
お口にあいますか？ お口にあうといいな♪
Does it suit your taste? I hope it suits you♪
Smile! Sweet! Sister! Sadistic! Surprise! Service! We are スティーレ!!
Smile! Sweet! Sister! Sadistic! Surprise! Service! We are Stile!!
さぁ扉を開けて 未知なるパラダイス 体験しよう おいで おいでYOU
Come on, open the door! Experience an unknown paradise, come on, come on YOU!
そうキミを待つのは 不思議なオアシス ほっこり日常に ちょっとぱりSpice
Yes, what's waiting for you is a mysterious oasis, add a little spice to your cozy daily life
ぐーるんぐーるん 当店自慢のフレーバー サービスサービス ご褒美タイム
Spinning and swirling, our shop's proud flavor, service, service, reward time
Welcome to...
はるか 遠い 遠い 昔 巻き込まれた 首輪
A long, long time ago, far away, a cursed collar
人が 欲しい 人が 欲しい と叫ぶ 呪い の 首輪
The cursed collar screams, "I want people, I want people"
怒ら ないで 見捨て ないで どこも 行かないで ねぇ
Don't get angry, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere, hey
強く 締める 吐く まで 締める 人 が いない いない と
It strangles me tightly, till I could throw up, whenever there is no one, no one around
いい 成績 でしょう
Nice grades, huh?
ねぇ ねぇ いい 子 でしょう
Hey, hey, aren't I a good kid?
かわいい 子 でしょう
A cute kid, right?
ねぇ ねぇ 良い 子 でしょう 苦しい ねぇ
Hey, hey, aren't I a good kid? It hurts, hey
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more
愛して 愛して 狂おしい ほど に
Love me, love me, so much that it's maddening
苦しい 苦しい 呪縛 を 解い て 解い て ねぇ
It's painful, it hurts. Break, break this binding spell, okay?
止め られ ない ah
It can't be stopped, ahh!
身体 身体 大きく なっても 小さい 首輪
Even if your body grows big, your neck will still be small
苦しく なる 足りなく なる 人 が 人 が 足りない
It becomes painful and not enough, people, people are not enough
クラス の 誰 に も 負けない キレイ な い い 子 でしょう ねぇ
I won't lose to anyone in my class, aren't I a pretty good child, hey?
あの 子 より も どの 子 より も 誰 も 彼 も 私 を 見て よ
More than that girl, more than any girl, everyone, everyone look at me
体育館 裏 あなた に 告白 を
Behind the gymnasium, I confess to you
嘘 みたい でしょう
It sounds like a lie, right?
あなた が 好き な の 汚い あなた が
I like you, even your dirty self
愛して 愛して 愛して 全部 あげる
Love me, love me, love me, I will give you everything
あなた に あなた に 全部 背負っ て もらう よ
You will carry everything on you, you who are not enough
足りない あなた が 足りない 離さ ないよ ah ごめんなさい
Not enough, you are not enough. I won't let go, ah, I'm sorry
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more
愛して 愛して 狂おしい ほど に
Love me, love me, so much that it's maddening
苦しい 離さ ない 苦しい もっともっと ねぇ
It hurts, don't let go, it hurts, more and more, hey
幸せ なの ah 幸せ なの ah
I'm happy, ah / This is happiness, ah
あの 国 より も どく より も あれ も これ も 私 呼んで よ
More than that country, more than anyone, everyone, everyone call for me
夜毎 肉感 顔出せ
Every night, showing my flesh and face
あなた に 告白 を 嘘 みたい でしょ
I confess to you, it sounds like a lie, right?
あなた が 好き な の 捨て ない で あなた を
I like you, don't throw me away
愛して 愛して 愛して 全部 上げる あなた に
Love me, love me, love me, I'll give it all to you
あなた に 全部 背負っ て もらう よ 足りない
You'll carry it all for me, it's not enough
あなた が 足りない 話さ ない よ ああ
You're not enough, I won't let go, ah
ごめんなさい 愛して 愛して 愛して
I'm sorry, love me, love me, love me
愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, more and more
愛して 愛して 狂おしい ほど に
Love me, love me, so much that it's maddening
苦しい ほど に 苦しい 苦しい
To the point of agony, painful, painful
離さ ない 苦しい もっと もっと ねぇ
Don't let go, it hurts, more and more, hey
もっと もっと ねぇ
More and more, hey
幸せ な の ah 幸せ な の ah
I'm happy, ah, this is happiness, ah
幸せ な の ah
I'm happy, ah
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Spoiling the romance sounds like "goodbye"
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spoiling life sounds like "death"
なにそれ意味深でかっこいいじゃん
What's with that? It's so profound and cool...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ 失敬
Dancing around with words that sound about right, excuse me.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅるる ほっ
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu...
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
It's just like that!
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅるる ほっ
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu...
神っぽいな あー
That's so god-like.
もういいぜもういいぜそれもいいぜもういいぜ
Enough's enough, on the contrary...
逆に興奮してきたな
I'm getting so excited!
おっきいねおっきいね 夢おっきいねおっきいね
It's so big, so big, my dream...
景気いいけど品性はTHE END
Business is booming, but graciousness is THE END
うええ うええ
Ueei, ueei
"Gott ist tot"
神っぽいな それ 卑俗
That's so god-like, how cowardly
神っぽいな それ My God
That's so god-like, that's "My God"
アイウォンチュー ウォンチュー
I want you, want you,
IQが下がっていく感じ
feeling my IQ drop away.
邪心っぽいな それ 畢竟
That's so evil-minded, after all
邪心っぽいな それ My God
That's so evil-minded, that's "My God"
アイヘイトュー ヘイトュー
I hate you, hate you,
害虫はどっち
which one is the pest?
その髪型 その目 その口元 その香水 その服 そのメイク
That hairstyle, eyes, mouth, perfume, outfit, makeup...
アレっぽいな それ 比況
That's so like that, how imitative
アレっぽいな それ
That's so like that
その名言 その意見 その批評 そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
Those quotes, opinions, criticisms, charisma, gags, sense...
神っぽいな それ 卑俗
That's so god-like, how cowardly
ぽいな ぽいな ぽい
Like that, like that, like that
憧れてしまう!
I admire it!
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅるる ほっ
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu...
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
It's just like that!
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅるる ほっ
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu...
ないいってんの? それ うざい
What are you talking about? That's annoying
ないいってんの? それ
What are you talking about? That...
意味がよくわかんないし
I don't really get it at all
眠っちまうよ マジ
I'm gonna fall asleep, seriously
飽きっぽいんだ オーケー
Everyone gets bored easily, okay?
みんな飽きっぽいんだ オーケー
踊れるやつ ちょうだい ちょうだい ビーム
Give me a beam, someone who can dance
キスほいね キスほいね それ
Give me a kiss, a kiss, that's it
キスほいね キスほいね
Give me a kiss, a kiss
逆にファンになってきたじゃん
On the contrary, I'm starting to become a fan
ちっちさいね ちっちさいね 器
It's so small, so small, your vessel
ちっちさいね ちっちさいね
It's so small, so small
天才ゆえ孤独ですね かっけー…
So lonely because you're a genius, how cool...
かっけー…
How cool...
"Gott ist tot"
神っぽいな それ 卑俗
That's so god-like, how cowardly
神っぽいな それ My God
That's so god-like, that's "My God"
超健康 健康 言い張って
Insisting on being super healthy
くたばっていく感じ
Ending up dropping dead
ヤケっぽいな それ 畢竟
That's so despairing, after all
ヤケっぽいな それ My God
That's so despairing, that's "My God"
もう哀愁 哀愁
Already sorrow, sorrow
エピゴーンの生息域
Habitual habitat of epigones
そのタイトル その絵 そのストーリー その音楽 その歌 そのメロディ
That title, art, story, music, song, melody...
アレっぽいな それ 比況
That's so like that, how imitative
アレっぽいな それ
That's so like that
その名言 その意見 その批評 そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
Those famous quotes, opinions, criticisms, charisma, gags, sense...
神っぽいな それ 卑俗
That's so god-like, how cowardly
ぽいな ぽいな ぽい
Like that, like that, like that
憧れちゃうわ!
I admire it!
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅるる ほっ
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu...
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
It's just like that!
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅるる ほっ
Tu-turu-tu-tu-turu...
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Spoiling the romance sounds like "goodbye"
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spoiling life sounds like "death"
すべて理解して患った
Understood everything and fell sick
無邪気に踊ってたおまじない人生
A pure life wanting to keep dancing.
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
There are no flowers prettier than artificial ones
何故ならば全ては嘘で出来ている
Because everything is made of lies
antipathy world
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて 湿らす前髪とこころの裏面
The rain of despair pierces my umbrella, dampening bangs and heart
煩わしいわ
How bothersome
何時しか言の葉は疾むに枯れきっている 事の真実があたしに熟れている
Before I knew it, words withered, and reality ripens within me
鏡に映り嘘を描いて 自我を見失った絵画
Reflected in the mirror, painting lies, losing sight of myself
パパッパラパッパララッパッパ 謎々交えて遊びましょう
Pa-pappara-pappara-rappappa, let's count riddles and play
タタッタラタタッタララタッタ 何故何故此処で踊っているのでしょう
Ta-tattara-tattara-ratatta, why are we dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand simple things
あたしって何だっけ
What was I again?
それすら夜の手に見絆れて
Even that is caught in the hands of night
愛のように消える
Disappearing like love
さようならも言えず囀っていた
Crying without even being able to say goodbye
フォニー フォニー フォニー 嘘に絡まっているあたしは
Phony, phony, phony, tangled up in lies, I am...
パパッパラパッパララッパッパ
Pa-pappara-pappara-rappappa
謎々数えて遊びましょう
Let's count riddles and play
タタッタラタタッタララタッタ
Ta-tattara-tattara-ratatta
何故何故ここで踊っているんでしょう
Why are we dancing here?
簡単なことも分からないわ
I don't even understand simple things
あたしって何だっけ
What was I again?
それすら夜の手にほろされて
Even that is destroyed by the hands of night
愛のようにさよならも言えぬまま
Without even being able to say a goodbye like love
泣いて 泣いて 泣いて 朝に絡まっている
Crying, crying, crying, tangled in the morning
あたしはフォニー
I am phony
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
In this world, flowers that are prettier than artificial ones don't exist,
何故ならば総ては嘘で出来ている
because everything is made of lies.
antipathy world,
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突きって
despair's rain pierces my umbrella,
湿らす前髪とこころの裏面
wetting my bangs and the back of my heart.
煩わしいわ
It's annoying.
何時しか言葉の葉は疾むに枯れきって
Words wither away before I even notice,
事の実はあたしに熟れている
and reality matures for me.
鏡に映り嘘を描いて
Reflected in the mirror, painting lies,
自らを見失った絵画
a picture where I lost myself.
何故何故此処で踊っているのでしょう
Why, why am I dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand simple things.
あたしって何だっけ
What was it I called myself?
それすら夜の手に見絡縛されて
Bound by the hands of night,
愛のように 消える
it fades away just like love.
さようならも言えぬ嚠喨いた
I mumbled an unspoken "farewell,"
嘘に絡まっている
tangled up in lies.
antipathy world,
何時しかそらの音がいやに鳴り合って
the sounds of the sky echo annoyingly,
色の目があなたを融かしている
and the colorful eyes melt into you.
鏡に映るあたしを欠いて
Flawed, reflecting in the mirror,
誰しもが見間違えた虚像
an imaginary figure everyone mistook.
如何して愛なんものに群がり
How is it that people swarm to things like love,
それを欲して生きるのだ
and live wanting them?
今日も泳いでいる夜の電車が通り過ぎていく、
Tonight too, the night train passes by, swimming along.
踊り明かせよ
Dance and let it bright!
何故何故此処が痛むのでしょう
Why, why does it hurt right here?
々々な日々は変わらないわ
These ordinary days never change.
絶望の雨は止まないわ
The rain of despair won't stop.
さようならも言えぬ嚠喨いた
I mumbled an unspoken "farewell,"
嘘に絡まっている
tangled up in lies.
フォニー、フォニー、フォニー
Phony, phony, phony,
嘘に絡まっているあたしは
tangled up in lies, I am...
フォニー
Phony.
お疲れが知っている秘密のフォニー
A secret known only to the tired you and me.
はい、というわけでいかがでしたか?
And with that, how was it?
愛して愛して愛して
I love you, love you, love you,
そして神っぽいな、そしてフォニーで
and most importantly, Phony!
お送りいたしました!
I sent it to you!
えみーな、どう?
Emi, how was it?
かっこよかった?
Was it cool?
可愛かった?
Was it cute?
え、どうかな?
Hey, I wonder if...
かっこよかった。嬉しい!
Ah, it was cool. I'm so happy!
そんなの、今回ね、ステージのね
So, for this time's stage,
このかっこいい映像とともに
we made it with this cool video,
お願いいたしまして、
and I requested it!
そしてね、
And you know what?
ダンスもめちゃめちゃかっこよかったでしょ?
The dance was also super cool, right?
これ、
This...
めちゃめちゃ難しかった。
was super, super difficult.
あれ、みんなもしやして、
Oh, everyone, by any chance...
さっきもちらちらコメント見えたけど、
I saw a few comments earlier, but...
そうなんですよ。
That's right, you see,
ロボコの頭をご覧ください。
look at Roboco's head.
こちら!
Here!
え、どうこれ?
How is it?
あらあら。
My, my, my, my.
みんないっぱいほらカメラさんも寄って、
Everyone, look, camera people too,
スクショしていっぱい撮ってほしい。
please take lots of screenshots!
ここ初お披露目だからね。
Because I'm revealing it for the first time!
と、かわいいでしょ?コン、コン!
Isn't it cute? Kong, kong!
コン、コン!
Kong, kong!
そうなんですよ。
That's right, so everyone,
ぜひね、このスクショもみんな撮ってくれたら
please take screenshots of this too!
ロボこの可愛さみんな広めていって!
Everyone, spread Roboco's cuteness,
頼むぞ!
please!
あ、チャンネル登録、高評価してないやつは
Oh, those who haven't subscribed or liked,
いないよね?
aren't there, right?
まさか!
No way!
さてね、かっこいい曲が続いたわけなんですけれども、
Well then, cool songs have continued,
ロボコ実は
Roboco actually...
もうちょいかっこいい曲歌いたいなと思ってて、
wants to sing an even cooler song,
どうやら別ステージで
Well, on a different stage,
なんかめっちゃかっこいい女たちの匂いがするからコンコン。うん。
there's a scent of really cool women, so kong-kong, um...
あ、あっちかな?ちょっと今ちょっとキツネのお面つけてるから自信ないけど。
Is it that way? I'm wearing a kitsune mask so I'm not sure, but...
嗅覚が、うん、こんこん、うん、
My instincts are... un, kong-kong.
匂いはこれ?あ、匂いまずね。
Is this the scent? Ah, the scent first, right?
じゃあちょっと向こうに大ジャンプしてみようかな?
Then, let's do a big jump over there!
それでは行くぞ!
Then, here we go!
Femme Fatale
作詞：Reol 作曲：Reol・Giga
Lyrics/Composition: Reol / Giga
We are 中王区 マイク片手に
We are Chuo-ku, mic in hand,
分かち易す勧告
handing down warnings.
We are 中王区 Check it out
We are Chuo-ku, Check it out,
We are 言の葉党
We are the Word Party.
さあ堂々とお通りです
Now proudly passing by,
音と言葉を侍らす
attending with sound and words,
そこ退け男共
move aside, you men.
さながらモゼ こちら東西天
Like a mozo, right this way to the Eastern Heaven,
乙統女の意のままに進むOK
proceeding just as the maiden wills, OK.
サービスにつけるハンディ ご覧遊ばせ
A handicap attached to the service, behold and enjoy,
これが私のマニフェストばり
this is my manifesto.
頭が高いですね
You're too high and mighty,
敵にもならない
you can't even be an enemy.
噛み付くのおなし いらないビーフ
No need for bickering or useless beef,
気安く呼んであるなよお前地下
don't call on us so casually.
Bad Queensの罠にハマれ
Caught in the trap of the Bad Queens,
上がるしかない支持率
approval ratings can only go up.
Lipsから韻律まで固め
Solidified from lips to rhyme,
ほらTopしか似合んこの運命
look, only the top suits this fate.
足りん脳で覚えとけよ名前
Memorize it deep within your brain.
もっと試したい オンナね
An ambitious woman, wanting to test more,
金の工面
arranging funds,
あげろの所作
raise your demeanor,
Shut up, shut up
そんなんじゃダメ
that's no good.
生ぬるい 滑稽な言葉じゃ飛べないでしょ？
You can't fly with such lukewarm, pathetic words, right?
あー 一歩先にもリスク まだでしょ 羽ばもう結構
Ah, there's a risk just a step ahead, not yet, flapping is plenty.
あー 手が離れるよざれと
Ah, your hand will slip away playfully,
私眠 これがマスターピース
I sleep, this is a masterpiece.
血を吸わことダマに宿すなよ おら
Don't harbor the act of sucking blood in your words, hey!
右へ左へ さあ堂々進め 我らが革命のショー
To the right, to the left, come on, advance proudly, our revolutionary show.
最後に笑うのは乙女
The one who laughs last is a maiden.
西へ東へ さあ頂上目指せ 我らが革命のショー
To the west, to the east, come on, aim for the summit, our revolutionary show.
もっと試したい オンナね
An ambitious woman, wanting to test more,
We are Chu-Oh-ku
片手には烏合の衆 Chu-Oh-ku
in one hand, a rabble, Chu-Oh-ku.
Check it out We are Chu-Oh-ku
限界は這い寄るボーナス あげてクレーム クソヘタな展開の現在に満満無い起死回生
Limits are creeping bonuses, raise complaints, a hopeless development of current resurrection.
Hands up, Hands up 意味から速攻見失う連鎖
Hands up, Hands up, a chain where meaning is instantly lost.
怖いよから手いばんでてぱ
Scared, so put on airs,
取りまとめるビート上から俺ディディダー
compile beats from above, alright.
決めたターゲット お次誰 言の葉スクラクラさせてくことの歯の応戦
Chosen target, who's next? Let Kotonoha scratch, battle of words.
切り開く見え透く何のこれしき
Cut open, see-through, nothing of the sort,
お手本の本二人にお任せ
leave it to the two role models.
波風見たくら白々音まねごとバックホン
White noise, mimicking sounds like a back horn,
実付けの行き届いたこのメロン 好きの出汁が売りですされでこー
this well-cared melon, favorite broth is for sale.
右へ左へ さあ堂々進め 我らが革命のショー
To the right, to the left, come on, advance proudly, our revolutionary show.
最後に笑うのは乙女
The one who laughs last is a maiden.
西へ東へ さあ頂上目指せ 我らが革命のショー
To the west, to the east, come on, aim for the summit, our revolutionary show.
もっと試したい オンナね
An ambitious woman, wanting to test more,
応答せよ 応答せよ
Respond, respond,
満たす息様の情報戦 応答せよ
information war filling breaths, respond,
三人寄ればたちまちかしまし交ぼせ 応答せよ
three people together instantly noisy, respond,
言の葉長が皿をきれいに刻め Oh yeah
Kotonoha chief cleanly carves plates, Oh yeah,
さあ革命の時間だ
now is the time of revolution.
We are Chu-Oh-ku 片手には烏合の衆 Chu-Oh-ku
We are Chu-Oh-ku, in one hand, a rabble, Chu-Oh-ku.
Check it out We are Chu-Oh-ku ことが端から
Check it out, We are Chu-Oh-ku, things from the edge.
We are Chu-Oh-ku 弁走らずとっくに中途
We are Chu-Oh-ku, halfway without running.
We are Chu-Oh-ku check it out We are ことが端から
We are Chu-Oh-ku, check it out, We are things from the edge.
言の葉の刃
The blade of words.
決死の初月の技ひとつ
One technique of the desperate first moon.
空をえら無双出し
Choosing the sky, unrivaled output.
おら見ろ他と違うテク 我らの品格を誇ら Check it out We are 言の葉の刃
Hey look, technique different from others, pride in our dignity, Check it out We are the blade of words.
あー！猫耳ー！すいちゃん猫耳ー！
Ah! Cat ears! Suisei cat ears!
え、かわいい〜！ふたり、とことこりに来たはずなんだけど
Eh, so cute! You two were supposed to come trotting over...
あれ？ かっこいいふたり？ ようこそいらっしゃいました
Huh? A cool duo? Welcome.
こんにちは、星街すいせいです。
Hello, I'm Hoshimachi Suisei.
猫又おかゆです。
I'm Nekomata Okayu.
かっこいいふたりで、やっぱりさっきのギャングだよね！
Such a cool duo, you really are the gang from earlier!
あー！猫耳ー！すいちゃん猫耳ー！
Ah! Cat ears! Suisei cat ears!
どうやら4周年のようですね。 おめでとうございます。
It seems to be the 4th anniversary. Congratulations.
おめでとうございます。あれ？
Congratulations. Huh?
ちょっとなんか、ロボ子の、夢かもしれないけど、ほっぺ引っ張ってもらってもいいかな？
Wait, this might be Roboco's dream, but could you pull my cheek?
ぶ、痛い！
Ow, ouch!
4年間よく頑張りました。 頑張りましたね。
You've worked hard for 4 years. You really did.
ありがとうございます！やっぱりかっこいいふたりでうれしいな！
Thank you! I'm so glad to have this cool duo!
あー！猫耳ー！すいちゃん猫耳ー！
Ah! Cat ears! Suisei cat ears!
あなたもどうぞ、どうぞ。
You too, go ahead.
あー！猫耳ー！すいちゃん猫耳ー！
Ah! Cat ears! Suisei cat ears!
猫耳はダメですね、猫耳はダメです。
Cat ears are no good, cat ears are no good.
猫耳はダメなんだね。猫耳はダメらしい。
Cat ears are no good, huh. Apparently cat ears are no good.
4周年で一緒にかっこいい曲を歌ってくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you for singing such a cool song together for the 4th anniversary.
いえ、どういたしまして。
Not at all.
呼んでくれてありがとう。
Thanks for inviting us.
ありがとうございます！なんと驚きの帽子あるんですね、僕たち。
Thank you! Surprisingly, we have hats, don't we?
そうです、可愛い、かっこいい、素敵、素敵、素晴らしい。
That's right, cute, cool, lovely, lovely, wonderful.
素敵、かっこいい、とても似合っているわ。
Lovely, cool, it suits you very well.
はい、ありがとう。
Yes, thank you.
もうラップに全力を使い果たしてMCをしゃべる頭はもうありませんよ。
I've used all my energy on the rap, I have no brain power left to talk on the MC.
もう分かりません、何を言ったらいいのかしら。
I don't know anymore, what should I say?
その帽子に脳を詰めることを忘れてしまったわ！
I forgot to pack brains into that hat!
あー！猫耳ー！すいちゃん猫耳ー！
Ah! Cat ears! Suisei cat ears!
かっこいい、かっこいい、猫耳は似合ってないじゃないか、星街！
Cool, cool, cat ears don't suit you, Hoshimachi!
そうですね。
That's right.
似合ってるな お前
You look good, you know.
自前です
It's my own.
こっちも
This one too.
これ 今日ロボ子ちょく先生に予約をしたんだけど
I made a reservation with Choku-sensei today, but...
大変高かったです
it was terribly expensive.
見てる子もしかしてない?これちょく先生のだよ
Kids watching, maybe not? This is Choku-sensei's, you know.
ちょく先生 こちらの椅子とても大変高かったです
Choku-sensei, this chair was terribly expensive.
で 星街が座るとねちょっとねお嬢ちゃまっぽくなっちゃうんだよね
And when Hoshimachi sits on it, she looks a bit like a little miss.
確かに
True.
なんで? そんなことない!
Why? That's not true!
だからこんなに今日お嬢ちゃま水星なのか?
So is today's Hoshimachi a little miss Suisei?
お嬢ちゃま水星じゃない!
I'm not little miss Suisei!
ちがう ちがう ちがう 取ったら誰よりも背が高いからね
No, no, no. If you take it off, you're taller than anyone else.
一番ちっちゃいんじゃないの
Aren't you the smallest?
そんな そんな そんな そんな
No... no... no... no...
すいちゃん お粥が意外と背が高い
Suisei, Okayu is surprisingly tall.
ちょっと私も今びっくりしました
I was quite surprised just now too.
おかゆちゃんに負けた! 残念でした!
Lost to Okayu! Too bad!
どうやら次はかわいい子が待っているらしいですけど
Apparently, a cute girl is waiting for us next, though.
え? うさぎの子かしら?
Eh? A rabbit girl, I wonder?
もうそんな時間?
Is it already that time?
やばい!じゃあロボ子ちょっとこの帽子脱ぎ捨てて かわいいかっこしなくちゃ!
Oh no! Then Roboco, throw off this hat and make yourself look cute!
がんばって おくん魂
Do your best, Okun-spirit!
お前 お前迷子すぎるだろ! なんでそんな間違ってんだよ 難しいだよ
You are way too lost! Why are you so mistaken, it's so hard!
じゃあロボ子行ってくるからね またね!行ってらっしゃい!ばいばーい!
Well, Roboco is heading out, see you later! Have fun! Bye-bye!
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
Romance scandals won't escape. I'll make them disappear.
シル・ヴ・プレジデント
S'il vous président!
宣誓! 私が大統領になったら
Oath! If I become president,
人の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします
women who meddle with other people's men will be exiled!
宣誓! 僕が大統領になったら
Oath! If I become president,
やたら友達だよ~って誤魔化す奴は巣から電流を流します
guys who brush it off saying "we're just friends~" will get shocked from their nests!
だ・だ・だ・大胆不敵
B-B-B-Bold and fearless,
センセーションナルクローズアップ
sensational close-up!
D,D,D,Don't cry
やるぜ徹底的にリサーチだ
I'll thoroughly research everything!
大嫌い?
You hate it?
しょうがない?
Can't be helped?
クズは病気ね
Scum are sick,
バイバイ・バイ
bye-bye-bye!
権力! 財産! 地位名声!!
Power! Fortune! Status and fame!!
なにもないけど裁いてみたいでしょ?
You have nothing, but you'd love to judge, right?
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね
If I become president,
まずは君を捕まえるね
first I'll catch you,
濡れたタオルで洗いさらい吐かせるね
and make you spit it all out with a wet towel!
(だ・だ・だ!)
(B-B-B!)
誰ですか あの女 (いやぁ~)
Who is that woman? (Oh my~)
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
Romance scandals won't escape. I'll make them disappear.
宣誓! 私が大統領になったらただの仕事の付き合いだよ?って言う奴は二度と働けなくしてやります
Oath! If I become president, guys who say "it's just a business relationship?" will never be able to work again!
宣誓! 以下略! いや向こうが強引でさ~っていう男の口にはレジンを流し込んで固めてやります!
Oath! Et cetera! I'll pour resin into the mouths of guys who say "she was the aggressive one~" and harden it!
み・み・み・密着
C-C-C-Close contact,
まるでドン・ファン気取りスキャンダラス
acting like Don Juan, scandalous!
ま・ま・ま・末端価格
Retail price,
甲斐性なしのスコップね
a scoop without financial capability!
愛はない?
No love?
理由じゃない?
Not the reason?
悪くないのね
Not bad, huh?
はいはいはいはい
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
軽薄! のうのう! いけしゃあしゃあ!!
Frivolous! Smug! Shameless!!
だ・だ・だ・大統領になってもね
Even if I become president,
たぶん君は変わらないね
you probably won't change.
本気ですか?
Are you serious?
そうですか(ほらん~)
Is that so? (Look~)
情熱とは不注意
Passion is carelessness,
微熱も消してしまいたいね
I want to erase even a slight fever.
でっ、どうする?今晩は
So, what will you do tonight?
本気ですか? そうですか ほらっ
Are you serious? Is that so? Look,
夜寝巣とは不注意 不治の病も
carelessness during sleep is an incurable disease,
消してしまいたい
I want to erase it completely!
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね
If I become president,
マジで君を捕まえるね
I'll seriously catch you,
濡れたタオルで洗いさらい吐かせるね
and make you spit it all out with a wet towel!
どこですか 今あんた 見つかっちゃった バレちゃった (あらぁ!)
Where are you now? You've been found out, exposed! (Oh my!)
夜道にはご用心 さようなら代わりに銃声
Watch your step on the dark streets. Goodbye, replaced by a gunshot!
代わりに忠誠 シル・ヴ・プレジデント
Loyalty instead. S'il vous président!
ロボ子先輩!
Roboco-senpai!
よーしね、お前ぺこー!
Alright, you Pekora!
ロボ子先輩! よーしね!
Roboco-senpai! Alright!
オリンペコ! オリンペコ! オリンペコ!
Olympeko! Olympeko! Olympeko!
いや一緒にシル・ヴ・プレジデント歌えてめちゃめちゃ
Singing "S'il vous président" together was so much fun!
ぺこらぴこ？
Pekora-piko?
いやロボ子とめっちゃ嬉しいよ！
Roboco, I'm super happy!
いや楽しい、あ、あれ？てか、あれ？
It's fun—wait, huh? Wait, what?
今更ながら気づいたぺこだけど、あれ？
I just noticed this now, but wait...
ぺこーらとロボ子先輩、あ
Pekora and Roboco-senpai, ah...
うさみみが
Rabbit ears...
あれ？おそろ、ち、おそろいじゃないですか！
Wait, we match—no, aren't they matching?!
そうなんだよぺこら！
That's right, Pekora!
もしやペコランドに来るためにうさみみをはやしてくれたということぺこな？
Could it be you grew rabbit ears to come to Pekoland?
いや全然それ関係ないけど。
No, that has nothing to do with it at all.
え、ちがうぺこ？
Eh, really?
いや全然関係ない、たまたまなきど
No, it's totally unrelated, it just happened to be—
あ、そうそう
Ah, right, right.
でもロボ子は、このシルフプレジデントをぺこらと歌いたくて！
But Roboco wanted to sing "Sylph President" with Pekora!
え、本当ぺこ？
Eh, really, Pekora?
で、このダンスがロボ子実はお気に入りであ
And this dance is actually Roboco's favorite—
わかりますよ、サビのところじゃないぺこですか？
I know, isn't that the chorus part?
いや、めちゃめちゃわかるじゃん。
Yeah, you totally get it.
え、じゃあ、え、一緒に、じゃあ、ここだよ、ね、ていうやつやります？
Eh, then, let's do the "Right here, right?" part together?
あ、いいよよ、行くよ？
Ah, sure, ready?
せーの、ここ、ここ
Ready, here, here—
待ってちょっと、ロボ子先輩のそれ、サビ前ぺこじゃないですか！
Wait a sec, isn't that before the chorus, Roboco-senpai?!
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
な、完璧にサビって言ってたじゃないですか！
You said it was definitely the chorus!
でもここ好きなんだもん。
But I like this part.
わかりますぺこ、ですけど、もうちょっとしっかりしてください、ぺこらの先輩！
I understand, Pekora, but please be a bit more reliable, Pekora's senpai!
う、それほどでも。
Uh, not quite that much.
それ褒めてねぇぺこから！
That's not a compliment, Pekora!
いやでも、本当に踊りたくて、で、せっかくだったらロボ子とぺこらでちょっと反対の対象カラーで、同じうさみみにしたかったなって思って。
Roboco really wanted to dance, and since we had the chance, I thought it'd be cute if we had opposite accent colors and matching rabbit ears.
えー、嬉しいぺこ！嬉しいぺこ！
Aww, I'm so happy, Pekora!
どうみんな、これ可愛い？どうみんな？可愛いしょ？
Hey everyone, isn't this cute? Cute, right?
なんかポーズとるぺこ？ポーズなんか。
Should we strike a pose? Some pose.
なんかうさぎっぽいポーズ教えてよ。
Teach me a rabbit-like pose.
うさぎっぽいポーズ教えてる、ロボ子先輩。
Teaching rabbit-like poses, Roboco-senpai.
うさぎは分かりやすいぺこでしょ、さすがに。
Rabbits are easy to recognize, naturally.
あ、ぴょぴょぴょ！そうちゃーん！たくさん撮ってぺこら！
Ah, pyo pyo pyo! That's right! Take lots of photos, Pekora!
そう、みんなね、持ちこずいていっぱいスクショ撮って送ってよね！
Yeah, everyone, save it and take lots of screenshots to send us!
やらぺ、いやぺこーらとロボ子先輩とふたりきりってなかなかなくないですか？
Wait, isn't it rare to have just Pekora and Roboco-senpai together?
え、本当に珍しい。
Eh, really rare.
え、そうぺこよね？
Eh, right?
だから今日誘ったとき、どういうとき、ドキドキしてた。
So when I invited you today, I was all nervous.
え！
Eh?!
ぺこらもでも嬉しかったぺこけど、あのロボ子先輩から誘われたとき。
Pekora was happy too, when Roboco-senpai invited her.
本当？！
Really?!
しかもペコらこのシルフプレジデントめちゃめちゃ好きぺこだったから、本当にね嬉しかったぺこ。
And Pekora loved this Sylph President so much, so I was really happy.
確かにそれ言ってたわ。
That's true, you did say that.
もうやるってきて、嬉しかった。
When you said 'Let's do it,' I was so happy.
いや記念になったぺこらもね、でも本当にー
It's a memorable moment for Pekora too, but really—
え、ねぇペコら、ちょっと横向いてみよ。
Hey, Pekora, try turning sideways.
ロボコも一緒に横向くからさ。
Roboco will turn sideways with you.
え、なになに？
Eh, what what?
えと、奥見らさ、近くに、あ、近くに言われなくても分かったみたいだ。
Ah, you didn't even need me to say it, you figured it out.
おい！
Hey!
ロボ子先輩！
Roboco-senpai!
え、なに、なに、なに、なに？おめでとうの日だからって言っていいことと悪いことがあるっていうことなら、格差があると言っていいぺこなんだろ？
Eh, what's with that? Since it's celebration day, if there are things you should and shouldn't say, then saying there's a disparity is fair game, right?
え、なにも言ってないけどな。
Eh, I didn't say anything though.
これでもペコらまだあるほうだぞ！
Even so, Pekora is still on the better side!
いや確かにあった気がするけど。
Well, it feels like there was.
ロボ子のほうが
Roboco's side is—
いやロボ子先輩もうほんとに暴走！暴走！なんでロボットのくせに胸がここにあるわけないじゃん！
No, Roboco-senpai is going wild! Wild! Why would a robot have breasts there?!
ロボットだからいっぱいあるんだぞ！
Since she's a robot, she has plenty!
ひどいことペコな！
That's awful, Pekora!
いやしかし、でもほんとに4周年おめでとうございますペコね！
Well anyway, congratulations on your 4th anniversary, Pekora!
あ、ペコだよ！
Ah, it's Pekora!
なんかまた一緒に歌える機会があったら歌いたいペコね。歌おうね、またペコね。
If there's another chance to sing together, I'd love to sing again. Let's sing again, Pekora.
うん。
Yeah.
じゃあ、ロボ子は次の曲にいってみたいと思います！
Well then, Roboco would like to move on to the next song!
いってらっしゃい！
Have fun!
頑張ってペコ！ありがとうペコラー！
Do your best, Peko! Thanks, Pekora!
バイバーイ！また遊ぶぞー！
Bye-bye! Let's play again!
ごめんね 憧れてた 追いかけてた
I'm sorry, I looked up to you, I chased after you
いつまでも そうでいたかった
I always wanted to stay that way forever
完璧なあなた 嫌いになった
I came to dislike you, my perfect self
同じように 愛貰って育ったのに いつからか 差が開いてた
Even though we grew up receiving the same love, a gap formed before I knew it
八つ当たりだってしたかった
I even wanted to take my frustration out on you
ねえ メイビー
Hey, maybe
神様は 試練与えた 強く なれと
God gave me a trial, telling me to be strong
ウザい 平等なんて嘘つき
"Equality is annoying" is a lie
わかっているけど
Even though I know that
可愛いとか モテたいとか 諦めないの 女の女の子だし
Wanting to be cute or popular, I won't give up, I'm a girl after all
上品らしく（ひっ） 猫被り（にゃっ） オンリーワンだよ☆ 愛してね
Elegantly (hi), wearing a cat mask (nya), I'm the only one☆ Love me
生き方は 無限にある
There are infinite ways to live
お父さんの大げさな言葉
My father's exaggerated words
いじらしく（ひっ） 猫被り（にゃっ） 私らしく行こう
Lovingly (hi), wearing a cat mask (nya), let's live true to myself
暇じゃない人生 生きよう
Let's live a life with no time to spare
だって 理想言えばキリなくて
Because if you talk about ideals, there's no end
無いもの全部 欲しがって
Wanting everything that doesn't exist
鏡を 見たって溜息 はぁ〜
Even when I look in the mirror, I sigh, haa~
あなただって 悩んでいた
You were worried too
知らなかった
I didn't know that
みんなと同じだと知った
I learned we're all the same
ピンと張った糸 緩んでく
The tightly strung thread is loosening
うん メイビー
Yeah, maybe
神様は 楽しんでる 予想できない人を
God is having fun with people who can't be predicted
私は それ以上に 楽しんでやるぜ
I'll enjoy myself even more than that
勉強とか お仕事とか 諦めないの 女の女の子だし
Studying or working, I won't give up, I'm a girl after all
元気よく（ひっ） 愛想良く（にゃっ） たたまには クールに☆ 付いて来て
Cheerfully (hi), friendly (nya), sometimes coolly☆ Follow me
愛した分 愛されるの
You're loved as much as you love
蔑まれそな劣性隠す
Hide the despised recessive nature,
故ここに立つ意味を持つ
Hence the meaning of standing here.
決した所依逃さず今探す理由
Why you should look for it now instead of running away,
変わらず細胞覚ます光よ
It's the light that awakens the cells unchanged.
i wanna renegade down
酔狂いそうな程の耳鳴りがした
Nearly intoxicating tinnitus,
ゆっくりと目を開けなければ
We must slowly open our eyes.
喪うもの選べない程
I can't choose what to mourn.
何かにつむる意志達よ
The will to cling to something,
荒んだ結晶持って
having a rough crystal...
どこに行こうかって言うんだよ
Where are we going to go?
生に拘ってない訳でもない揺れる未来
A shaky future not obsessed with life.
焦点距離が歪んでしまっただけで
The focal length just got distorted.
それですいいんだ
That's okay.
take away and do for me
答えのない世界でも
even in a world without answers.
carry on and burn it down
get away every bug
take away and do for me
滲んだこの声を
blotch this voice.
carry on and burn it down
you've got to be the one you want
そうやって自分を欺く事すら
Even fooling yourself like that
裏切りに変えてしまっていたから
because I had turned it into a betrayal.
憎しみとか哀れみさえ
Even hatred and pity,
自己犠牲で片付けたんだ
self-sacrifice and cleaned up.
take away and do for me
答えのない世界でも
even in a world without answers.
carry on and burn it down
get away every bug
蔑まれそな劣性隠す
Hide the despised recessive nature,
故ここに立つ意味を持つ
Hence the meaning of standing here.
決した所依逃さず今探す理由
Why you should look for it now instead of running away,
変わらず細胞覚ます光よ
It's the light that awakens the cells unchanged.
i wanna renegade down
take away and do for me
答えのない世界でも
even in a world without answers.
carry on and burn it down
get away every bug
take away and do for me
滲んだこの声を
blotch this voice.
carry on and burn it down
you've got to be the one you want
breathe in breath out fill out your voice
calling find out your name
this is your life
you never lose yourself
why don't you come
これらはピースの君
These are pieces of you.
why don't you come
peace out
breathe in breath out fill out your voice
calling find out your name
this is your life
you never lose yourself
why don't you come
これらはピースの君
These are pieces of you.
why don't you come
peace out
と、いうわけでNo.1でした！
And with that, that was No. 1!
すごい声出たんだけど、ちょっと待って。
Wait, my voice is so loud... Hold on.
え？
Huh?
あ、え？みんな、え？
Eh? Wait, everyone...
アイドル衣装にロボ子、なってるよこれ？
Roboco, is that you?
えっ！
Wait!
えっ、待って、お気づきの方？
Eh? Wait, did you notice?
オルユ？ロボ子、なん……他の3Dショーと
Or you? Roboco, wait, other 3D shows...
同じ衣装になっているんだけど！
Are they wearing the same outfit?
なんとアップデートされたアイドル衣装です！
What, it's an updated idol outfit!
どうりゃあ？どうりゃあ可愛いか？
How is it? How cute is it?
可愛い決まってんだよな！笑
It's obviously cute, right? Haha!
え、マジでいきなりレベッカにした。
Eh, seriously, I suddenly became a mecha?
このタイミングで本当合ってるのか？
Is this timing really correct?
合っています笑
It's correct. Haha!
はい、というわけで
Hi, so,
でもね、歌はもう終盤なんですよ。
well, the songs are already in the middle, right?
で、最後の曲はこのアップデートされたアイドル衣装で歌いたいなと思って、
So for the last song, I wanted to sing with this updated idol outfit,
先に着替え来ちゃいました！
so I went and changed early!
可愛いでしょう？ちょっと今のうちにね、いっぱいスクショ撮っといてください。
Cute, right? So make sure to screenshot a lot before this ends!
おはにゃーん！可愛い！ウィンク！プリーズ！
Heart hands! Cute! Wink! Please!
にぱにぱにぱにぱ！笑
Peace, peace, peace, peace! Haha!
はい、というわけで
Hi, so,
終盤ということは、もちろん
since it's the ending, of course...
グッズ紹介です！
Goods introduction!
はい、4周年記念グッズ、もちろん出すぞ！
Yes, the 4th anniversary goods, of course, let's show them!
それでは、上さん出したって！
Then, let's show them!
待ってください！
Wait a minute!
どうじゃ！
Ta-da!
はい、というわけでロボ子さん4周年活動記念グッズ発表したいと思います！
Hi, so... I'd like to announce my 4th anniversary merchandise!
それでは運営さん、1つ目を、どーん！
Well then, management, let's reveal the first one... boom!
はい、こちらですね。teffish先生のかきおろしのB2タペストリーとなっております。
Yes, here it is. This is a B2 tapestry with brand-new artwork by teffish-sensei.
めっちゃお姉さんでめっちゃ可愛くない？なのにロボ子、実はまだ5歳なので、食べれるようになったプリンとお子さまオムライス食べてます。
Isn't she super big-sisterly and adorable? But since Roboco is actually only 5, she's eating pudding and kids' omurice that she can now eat.
どう？このギャップ。5歳児のお姉さんはいかがですか？
How's that for a gap? What do you think of this 5-year-old big sister?
可愛いでしょ？これめちゃめちゃ可愛いよね。みんなも欲しくなっちゃったんじゃないの？どうよ？
Cute, right? This is super cute. Aren't you guys starting to want one too? Well?
あれ？ねえ。スプーンとフォーク、ちょっと……あれ？なんかそれまでロボ子のモチーフになってるの気づいちゃった人いるかな？
Huh? Hey. The spoon and fork... wait... Did anyone notice they're shaped like Roboco's motifs?
運営さん、ちょっと次のも見せてくださいよ。
Management, please show us the next one.
次！あー、そうなんです！なんとこちらですね、ロボ子が描きました、こち……
Next! Ah, that's right! Surprisingly, this one... Roboco drew it, here...
なんとこれロボ子が描きました。どーお？可愛くない？
Roboco drew this. How is it? Isn't it cute?
そう、ロボ子が描いた「ロボ子(リボン)バージョン」と「ロボ子(ツノお下げ)バージョン」となっております。
Yes, it's available in "Roboco (Ribbon Version)" and "Roboco (Horn Pigtail Version)" drawn by Roboco.
そうなんとに、初めてのカトラリーセットというわけでね、さっきのタペストリーにも混ざってました。
Yes, so, it's our very first cutlery set, and it was mixed into that tapestry earlier.
カ、カト、カトラリー……カト、カト、カトラリーって言ったのバカなんじゃないの誰か。知ってるか知らんけど。
Cu-cu-cutlery... Cut-cut-cutlery... Whoever said cutlery, aren't you stupid? Who knows, maybe.
ロボ子ポンしてないもん！ポンじゃないもん！
Roboco didn't pon! I'm not pon!
カトヤリー、こちらカトラリーですね。ええ、ポンはしてないので、買ってください！これで食べたら高精度に間違いなし！買ってね！うん。
Katoyary, this is cutlery. Um, I didn't pon, so please buy it! Eating with this is guaranteed high precision! Buy it, okay? Yeah.
ロボ子はこれでご飯を食べます！はい！二つぐらい買っとくとね、おすすめですよ。洗うのがね、一気にいっぱい使えるので。うんうんうん。
Roboco eats her meals with this! Yes! Buying about two is recommended, you know. Because you can wash a bunch of them at once. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
さあ、そしてですね、まだあるんですよ。それではこちらを、どーん！
Now, and you see, there's still more. Well then, for this one... boom!
はい、そうなんとランチプレート付き！どうこれ？ロボ子なんか結構こういうお皿が好きでさ、いつも普段使いしてるんだけどさ。
Yes, so surprisingly, it comes with a lunch plate! How's this? Roboco kind of likes these kinds of plates and uses them everyday,
やっぱさ、オリジナルバージョン欲しくなっちゃったから今回作ってみました、しりしよく。
but since I wanted an original version, I tried making one this time... selfishly.
もうほんまに今回しりしよくかもしれないけど、でもみんなご飯作りたいよね？
It might be really selfish of me this time, but everyone wants to cook rice, right?
ロボ子と一緒にご飯食べたいよね？
You want to eat meals with Roboco, right?
じゃあもうお皿もフォークもスプーンもロボ子とお皿にしよ！そういうことですよ。
Well then let's make the plate, fork, and spoon Roboco-themed too! That's what this is about.
これでロボ子と同じ料理間違いなし！一緒に料理しようね！さあそしてこちらのね、イラストが描いてあるんだけれども。
Guaranteed same dishes as Roboco with this! Let's cook together! Now, and the illustration drawn here...
こちらのイラスト、なんと。
...this illustration, surprisingly...
こちらにも出てきます。
...appears here too.
うっどーん！
Woo-boom!
はい、というわけでですね、こっちはアクリルキーホルダー、こちらはランダムのね、4種類となっております。
Yes, so this is the acrylic keychain, and this is random with 4 varieties.
はい、えーもう、めっちゃポン、ちょっとポン、なりかけ、えー。可愛い！可愛いの4種類となっております。
Yes, um, super pon, slightly pon, about to be... um. Cute! There are 4 cute varieties.
どうですか？こちらはですね、赤ババ先生がね、描き下ろしてくれたランダムキーホルダーとなっております。
How is it? This is a random keychain newly drawn by Akababa-sensei.
アクリルキーホルダーですね。え、もうどれも可愛いでしょう。でも、
Acrylic keychains. Um, aren't they all cute? But...
個人い的には……う、う、う、う、ボーンが好き。
...personally... I, I, I, I love Born.
めっちゃ可愛くないこのアフロ。やっぱアフロいいよな。
Isn't this Afro super cute? As expected, Afros are great.
そう、こちらですね、ランダムでありますので、皆さんぜひ全種類ゲット目指して頑張ってみてください！まあ、同じのいっぱいいやっても可愛いなって思っちゃうロボ子なんですけどね。うん。
So, this is random, so everyone please try your best to get all varieties! Well, even if you get duplicates, Roboco thinks it's cute though. Yeah.
はい、というわけで今回も活動4周年記念フルセット、数量限定版は、今言った全部そして……
Yes, so this time the 4th Anniversary Full Set, quantity-limited edition, includes everything I just mentioned and...
teffish先生のロボ子お姉さん風のお子様ランチ食べてるあのタペストリーの、え、ポストカードに直筆サイン、そして複製吐息メッセージ入りが入っているやつが……ご購入さ……
...teffish-sensei's postcard of Roboco big-sister style eating kids' lunch from that tapestry, with a handwritten signature and a duplicated sigh message included is... available for purchase...
言えなかった…
I couldn't say it...
ええ、導入されております！ドンッ！
Um, it has been introduced! Ta-da!
かわいいですよこれ、ポストカード！
Isn't this cute? A postcard!
と言うわけでね、こちら数量限定なのでみんなゲットしてくれよな！
That's why, this is limited in quantity so everyone make sure to get it!
今のうちに待機しとくんだぞ！この後ですからね。
Make sure to wait for it right now! Because it's coming up next.
はい、うるせえポンスタなんて…ポンは、ポンは日常だ。
Yes, calling me annoying "Ponstar"... Pon is, pon is daily life.
ポンは、ポンは日常だからもう諦めるロボ子！ポンと一緒にいけるんだ！
Pon is, pon is everyday life so I'll just give up, Roboco! I can go together with Pon!
はい、というわけでね、ま、もちろん数量限定版買えなくても、ポストカードね、ロボ子のね、サイン入り複製バージョンのね、やつありますので、メッセージ入りが。ぜひそっちのね、フルセットも購入してください！
Yes, so, of course, even if you can't buy the limited quantity version, there's postcards, Roboco's signed duplicate version, with a message. So please purchase the full set of those too!
はーい、というわけでね、いかがでしたか？
Right! So, how was it?
今日はなんか4周年だったけど、ポンっちゃったような気持くもないんですけれど。
Today was sort of the 4th anniversary, but I kind of feel like I made a mess of it.
まあ大丈夫だよね？うん。
Well, it'll be fine, right? Yeah.
ま、ね、最後はきっちり決めたいと思いますので、ロボ子の最後の曲、聞いてください。
Well, since I want to finish things properly, please listen to Roboco's final song.
このアイドル衣装にちなんだアイドル曲を歌わさせていただきます。
I'll be singing an idol song fitting for this idol outfit.
それでは聞いてください。
Now then, please listen.
私のこと知ってますか？ 可愛い見えてますか？
Do you know about me? Do I look cute?
私の歌どうだろうな うまく歌えてますか？
How is my singing? Am I singing well?
衣装とかメイクとか 可愛い見えてますか？
My costume and makeup, do I look cute?
振付とかファンサとかも 喜んでもらえますか？
My choreography and fanservice too, do they make you happy?
手は冷たくなって 足は震える
My hands are getting cold and my legs are shaking
それでも戦いたい
Even so, I still want to fight
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of me
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down on
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を 見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say words like "just an idol" when you haven't even seen me!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my hard work for granted
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force an image on me
“アイドルなんか”という言葉はこの世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "just an idol" are the one thing I hate the most in this world!
向かい風を切り裂け
Cut through the headwinds
誇り高きアイドル
A proud idol
目指そうぜ
Let's aim for it!
プライベート見えないから 分からないと思います
Private life is invisible so I think you wouldn't know
性格とか悪い方です 騙しちゃってますか？
My personality is pretty bad, did I manage to fool you?
でも本気です本気なんです ありのままの私を
But it's the truth, I'm serious, love me as I am
好きになって推して下さい それってワガママですか？
and become my fan, is that selfish?
きっと可愛くない全部分かってる それでも好かれたくて
I'm sure I'm not cute, I knew it all, but I still wanted to be liked
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
皮肉言う奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who say sarcastic things
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
I hate people who make excuses
“こんなもんか”という言葉を 軽々しく口にするな
Don't say words like "is that all?" so lightly!
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't set limits on me
笑い者に何てするな
Don't make a fool out of me
“アイドルなんか”という言葉はこの世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "just an idol" are the one thing I hate the most in this world!
向かい風を切り裂け
Cut through the headwinds
誇り高きアイドル
A proud idol
目指そうぜ
Let's aim for it!
応援がなければ活動できない 好きなことばかりじゃ生きてはいけない
Without support I can't work, I can't live doing only what I like
元気あげるはずがもらえてばかりだし 恩返しできる日まで待ってて
I'm supposed to give energy, but I receive it instead, wait until I can repay you
元気だとか本当はね 隠したって苦しくて
Even when hiding my true feelings, it hurts
それでも笑っていたい
Still wanting to smile
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
熱いファンの愛があって
With the love of passionate fans
With the love given by my passionate fans,
スタッフさんの愛があって
with the love given by the staff members,
いつも家族の愛があって
with the love my family have always given me,
生きてる“アイドル”
I continue to live as an idol.
アイドル
An idol.
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate the people who make fun of me
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I don't like to be looked down on either
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
And words like "idols are nothing"
見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say them when you haven't even actually seen them!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my hard work for granted
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force an image on me
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
And words like "idols are nothing"
この世で一番大嫌いだ
are the one thing I hate the most in this world!